A Guide to the Gertrude E. Perlmann papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA189
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Correspondence, 1944-1974
  - G-Go (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Gilvarg, Charles. Employment recommendation for Rosie Wong, 3 items
    - Glover, Betsy, 1962-1973; 7 items
    - Godin, Claude, 4 items
    - Goldstein, Leon, 1965-1974; 8 items
      Includes promotion recommendation for; Goldstein biographical material.
    - Goldstein, Ruth, 1967-1973; 25 items
      Includes items on visits to Weizmann Institute, Rehovoth, Israel; biographical material about A. Katzir-Katchalsky for possible award nomination.
  - Go-Gu (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Good, Mary L., 6 items
    - Goodman, Murray, 1 item
    - Gorbunoff, Marina J.
      (See under: American Society of Biological Chemists correspondence.) Box 4.
    - Goss, Barbara Job inquiry, 2 items
    - Goudsmit, S., 1 item
    - Gould, R. Gordon, 2 items
    - Gounaris, Anne D., 1964-1974; 32 items
      Staff appointment; recommendations for;.
      (See also under: American Society of Biological Chemists correspondence.).
    - Grabe, Barbro, 2 items
    - Grant, Diane, 5 items
    - Gratzer, Walter, 2 items
    - Greene, Joyce, 2 items
    - Greene, Lewis J., 2 items
    - Greenwald, Michael J. Job inquiry, 4 items
    - Gregor, Harry P., 2 items
    - Griffin, John H., 2 items
    - Grisolia, Santiago, 1 item
    - Grizzuti, Kärt. Concerning lab work when Dr. Perlmann away, 9 items
    - Gross, Erhard, 3 items
    - Gruber, M., 2 items
    - Grunberg, Manago, M., 2 items
    - Guggenheim, John Simon Memorial Foundation, 2 items
    - Gurnani, Shantoo, 3 items
    - Gustafson, Gunnar, 2 items
    - Guth, Eugene, 3 items
    - Guttman, Helen N., 4 items
  - H-Hel (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Haas, Werner, 2 items
    - Haddon Hall, 1 item
    - Halvorson, Professor, 1 item
    - Hamilton, Gordon A., 2 items
    - Hancock, Diane, 3 items
    - Handler, Philip On introducing P. Bentley paper at 1954 April meeting of American Society of Biological Chemists in Atlantic City, N.J., 1 item
    - Hanson, Jean, 1 item
    - Harington, Sir Charles, 1 item
    - Harrington, William F., 1958-1974; 56 items
      Includes: numerous items on pepsin-pepsinogen work; item on phosvitin work: recommendation for John Cebra; 1964 Feb. 22 Gordon Conference on Proteins in N.Y.C. at Sloan-Kettering; 1968 Nov. 26? Baltimore, Md., McCollum Pratt seminar.
    - Harris, Jacqueline L. Boston University, Department of Biochemistry seminar, 1966 May 3; 2 items
    - Harrison, Anna J., 1963 1973; 2 items
    - Hart, Jules, 2 items
    - Harte, Robert A., 1963-1974; 14 items
      Includes: item nominating Anne D. Gounaris for American Society of Biological Chemists membership; suggesting Poster Sessions for American Society of Biological Chemists meetings.
    - Hartley, Brian, 4 items
    - Hastings, A.B., 2 items
    - Haugaard, Niels, 2 items
    - Hayashi, Midori, 1 item
    - Hayashi, Teru NY City Columbia University seminar, 1963 March 15; 6 items
    - Hays, Richard M., 2 items
    - Heald, P.J., 1 item
    - Heidelberger, Michael, 2 items
    - Heilbronn, Edith, 1 item
    - Hele, Priscilla Job inquiry with curriculum vitae, 4 items
  - Hen-Hu (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Henlein, Lore Of American Elsevier Publishing Co., 23 items
      Includes reviews of:.
      Wieland & Pffeider (Eds.) "Molekular-Biologie".
      K.S. Spiegler - proposed "Steady-State Thermodynamics".
      P.J. Wheatley "Chemical Consequences of Nuclear Spin".
      Otto Redlich. "Thermodynamics".
      E. Buddecke "Grundriss der Biochemie".
    - Herriott, Doris E., 2 items
    - Herriott, Roger M., 3 items
    - Herrmann, Heinz, 4 items
    - Herrmann, Robert L. Boston University seminar, 1971 February?; 1 item
    - Hess, Eugene, 2 items
    - Hess, George P. Cornell University seminar on "Pepsin and pepsinogen" at Ithaca, NY, 1968 May 20; 4 items
    - Hevesy, Pia de, 4 items
    - Heyningen, Simon van, 3 items
    - Hill, Robert L., 1 item
    - Hillis, W.D., 1 item
    - Himmelfarb, Sylvia, 4 items
    - Hirs, C.H.W., 1973; 5 items
      Concerning nominations committee 1973, Division of biological chemistry, American Chemical Society.
    - Ho, Chien, 4 items
    - Hoberman, Henry D.NY City Albert Einstein College of Medicine seminar, 1963 May 13; 3 items
    - Hodgkin, Dorothy, 1 item
    - Hoegger, Jean, 1 item
    - Hoffman, Anna L. Concerning Iota Sigma Pi chapters, 1 item
    - Hofman, Theo, 2 items
    - Holasek, Anton, 3 items
      2 items in German.
    - Hollingworth, B.R. Recommendation for, 2 items
    - Holmes, K.C., 1 item
    - Holter, Heinz, 2 items
    - Hopkins, Esther A.H. Concerning Women Chemists Committee, American Chemical Society, 4 items
    - Horecker, B.L., 5 items
    - Horner, William H., 3 items
    - Horowitz, Martin I.NY City New York Medical College seminar, 1969 April 2; 2 items
    - Hrkal, Zbynek, 2 items
    - Huennekens, Frank, 2 items
    - Humphrey, John, 2 items
    - Hung, Pauline. Iota Sigma Pi meeting, 1962 May 5; 1 item
  - I-J (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Ichishima, Eija, 2 items
    - Imahori, Kazutomo, 1967 August; 5 items
      Includes items on pepsin-pepsinogen work;, Tokyo, Japan, International Congress of Biochemistry.
    - International Symposium on Conformational Analysis, 3 items
    - Israel Biochemical Society, 3 items
    - Jacobsen, Henning, 3 items
    - Jakus, Marie A., 1 item
    - Jirgensons, Bruno, 1960-1971; 8 items
      Includes recommendation for Dr. Nakagawa.
    - Johnson, Donald G., 1 item
    - Johnson, Paley, 4 items
    - Jones, J.H., 3 items
    - Jones, Mary Ellen, 16 items
      Includes biographical material and letters of recommendation from G.E. Perlmann, N.O. Kaplan, F. Lipmann for nominations for Iota Sigma Pi research award and Garvan award.
    - Journal of Biological Chemistry, 6 items
    - Jukes, Thomas H., 3 items
    - Jung Hotel
  - Katchalski, Ephraim, 1958-1973; 266 items (Box 6)
    Correspondence deals mainly with current work; collaboration; visits to Israel includes beginning with 1960 March, 6 months as visiting Professor in E. Katchalski laboratory with 3 months undated letters by O. Blumenfeld; many E. Katchalski handwritten items; includes material on E. Katchalski numerous visits to RI; 2 photographs 1960, 1969; recommendation for John Cebra. In 3 folders.
    - 1958-1962 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - 1963-1973 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - E. Katchalski laboratory correspondence, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      Correspondence received from RU lab while visiting Professor in E. Katchalski laboratory at Weizmann Institute in 1960.
      Correspondence deals mainly with laboratory experimental work:.
      Blumenfeld, Olga.
      Diringer, Renata.
      Eng, Betty (Hon).
      Johnston, Kathy.
      Lacock, E.S.
  - Katzir-Katchalsky, Aharon, 1961-1973; 73 items (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Correspondence deals mainly with current work; collaboration; visits to Israel.
    (See also under: Goldstein Ruth correspondence. Box 5; Sharon, Nathan correspondence. Box 9).
  - Ka-Kend (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Kac, Mark, 1 item
    - Kaiser, Emil T., 8 items
    - Kalckar, Herman M., 6 items
    - Kalckar, Jorgen, 4 items
    - Kaplan, Nathan O., 1961-1971; 9 items
    - Karasz, F.E., 2 items
    - Kassell, Beatrice, 1965-1968 23 January 1974; 30 items
      Includes 1968 Jan. 23 Milwaukee, Wise. Marquette Univ. School of Medicine seminar; items on pepsin-pepsinogen work; recommendation for.
    - Kauzmann, Walter, 1962-1974; 7 items
    - Kay, John, 2 items
    - Kedem, Ora, 3 items
    - Keil, B., 1960-1972; 29 items
    - Keller, Patricia, 5 items
    - Kendrew, John C., 16 items
  - Kenn-Ko (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Kennedy, Eugene, 1962-1966 April 30, 1971; 9 items
      Includes 1966 April 30 Harvard Medical School dinner invitation honoring Ephraim Katchalski.
    - Kerwar, Grace, 4 items
    - Kessler, John O., 14 items
    - Khan, Sohaib A., 6 items
    - Khorana, G.P., 1 item
    - Kirschenbaum, Donald M., 1 item
    - Kleiner, Israel S., 2 items
    - Klotz, I.M. Evanston, Ill. Northwestern University seminar, 1968 January 25; 9 items
    - Knowles, Jeremy R., 9 items
    - Koehn, Paul V., 1964-1969; 71 items
      Includes staff appointment; recommendations for; Koehn and Kind reprint; Koehn curriculum vitae.
  - Ko-Kw (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Koltun, Walter L., 15 items
    - Konigsberg, William H., 2 items
    - Kornberg, Arthur, 2 items
    - Kostka, Vladimir, 2 items
    - Kraut, Joseph, 1 item
    - Krebs, Edwin G., 4 items
    - Krimm, Samuel, 3 items
    - Krogmann, David W., 7 items
    - Kucar, Olga, 3 items
    - Kuck, Valerie J., 2 items
    - Kulka, R.G., 2 items
    - Kunkel, Henry
      (See under Muller-Eberhard, Hans correspondence. Box 7).
    - Kwei, K.P., 5 items
  - Linderstrøm-Lang, K., 1946-1959 1960-1964; 139 items (Box 7, Folder 1)
    (9 obituary articles ca. 1960-1964).
    Includes numerous letters about scientific work and comments on Perlmann mss; some holographs. 7 letters with Møller; some correspondence about Linderstrøm-Lang 1957 lectures at RI. Obituary articles, one in Danish and charter of Linderstrøm-Lang Foundation and some letters.
  - Longsworth, Lewis G., 1944-1957 1960 1966; 45 items (Box 7, Folder 2)
    Includes holographs.
  - L-Ly (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Ladman, John, 1 item
    - Laiken, Nora D., 1 item
    - Lambros, Joan P. Member of award committee of Iota Sigma Pi, 2 items
    - Lanclos, Kenneth D., 1 item
    - Lapanje, Savo, 2 items
    - Lapidot, Yehuda, 1960-1971; 21 items
      Includes recommendations for.
    - Lee, Y.C., 6 items
    - Lemoncelli, Elissa, 2 items
    - Lenard, Jean
      (See under: Lucas-Lenard, Jean correspondence. Box no. 7).
    - Léonis, José, 1957-1963; 8 items
      Includes staff appointment.
    - Lerner, H.D., 2 items
    - Levine, Lawrence, 2 items
    - Levinsky, Haim, 1 item
    - Levison, Stuart Job inquiry, 3 items
    - Levy, H. Richard, 1 item
    - Li, C.H., 1963 April 1; 9 items
      Includes Berkeley, California, University of California seminar.
    - Li, H.J., 2 items
    - Li, Y.T., 5 items
    - Lifson, Shneior, 3 items
    - Lillevik, Hans A., 2 items
    - Linderstrøm-Lang, C.U., 3 items
    - Lipkin, David, 1961 February 16; 6 items
      Includes Y. Lapidot recommendation; St. Louis, Mo. Biophysical Society seminar.
    - Lisco, Hermann, 2 items
    - Littauer, U.Z., 1 item
    - Lloyd, D.C.P. Congratulations on G.E. Perlmann promotion to full professorship, 2 items
    - Lobue, Bonnie, 1 item
    - Loewenstein, Martha, 1967-1974; 13 items
      Includes: Invitations to Annual Weizmann Institute dinners; gift for Aharon Katzir-Katchalsky Center.
    - Loftfield, Robert B., 3 items
    - Lontie, René, 3 items
    - Loomis, M.A., 2 items
    - Lorand, Joyce (Mrs. Laszlo), 3 items
    - Lorand, Laszlo, 1963-1974; 26 items
      Includes: 1964 Apr. 17 and 1974 Ca. Feb. 18 Northwestern Univ. seminars; some correspondence. on relationship with Academic Press and possibly? Methods in Enzymology.
    - Lotan, Noah, 1 item
    - Lowey, Susan, 2 items
    - Lucas-Lenard, Jean, 16 items
      Includes biographical material and letters of recommendation from G.E. Perlmann, S.S. Cohen, M. Grunberg-Manago, F. Lipmann, F.D. Vasington for nomination for Pfizer award.
    - Luck, David Wayne L. Hubbell evaluation, 1 item
    - Ludin, Adele On Iota Sigma Pi, 2 items
    - Lundberg, A. Stockholm, Sweden, International Congress of Biochemistry, 1973 July 1-7; 2 items
    - Lyons, David J., 1 item
    - Lyman, R.L., 2 items
  - M-Mul (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Makonnen, Belew Proteolytic Enzymes volume, 2 items (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Malkin, Charles, 1 item (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Mao, Thomas S.S., 2 items (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Marchaim, Toni Concerning Uri Marchaim, 1 item (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Marchaim, Uri Staff appointment; includes Marchaim et al reprints, 17 items (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Margoliash, E., 2 items (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Marks, Herman On attending, Aharon Katchalsky memorial seminar at Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn, 1973 February 3; 2 items (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Marks, Richard, 2 items (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Marshall, R.D., 5 items (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Martin, R. Bruce, 1 item (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Masone, E.D. Job inquiry, 2 items (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Matthews, Drue, 4 items (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Mauzerall, David C. On agreeing to participate in RU tutorial program, 1 item (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - May, Sheldon W., 2 items (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - McCarty, Maclyn On attending dinner honoring M. Sela preceding Harvey Lecture, 2 items (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - McDonald. Ken, 2 items (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - McFarlane, A.S., 2 items (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - McGavin, S., 3 items (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - McKenzie, H.A., 3 items (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - McMeekin, T.L. Congratulations on winning Garvan Award, 2 items (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Mehler, Alan H., 3 items (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Mellecker, John B., 3 items (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Meloun, B., 1 item (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Michaeli, I., 2 items (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Miller, Joyce, 2 items (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Miner, Eunice T., 4 items (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Mirsky, Sonia W. Concerning Ephraim Katchalski use of RU library, 1 item (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Monnier, A., 1 item (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Monroy, Alberto, 5 items (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Moore, Eunice M. Congratulations on winning Garvan Medal, 2 items (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Moràvek, Ladislav, 1 item (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Morrissey, S., 1 item (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Moy, Mamie W. On setting up Iota Sigma Pi chapter at University of Houston, 1 item (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Mueller, Frank H., 1 item (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Mukerjee, H. Job inquiry includes curriculum vitae, 6 items (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Muller-Eberhard, Hans, 6 items (Box 7, Folder 5)
      Includes biographical material about Henry Kunkel for possible award nomination; H. Muller-Eberhard holograph concerning Kunkel work.
    - Muller-Eberhard, Ursula, 1968-1974; 87 items (Box 7, Folder 5)
      Includes 1969 Mar. 3 La Jolla, Calif. Scripps Clinic and Research Foundation seminar; recommendation for; U. Muller-Eberhard biographical material.
  - Mun-My (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Muntinghe, Otto G., 2 items
    - Murachi, Takashi, 49 items
      Includes Murachi family photograph; Murachi ms with comments.
    - Murphy, James S., 1 item
    - Murray-Lyon, Iain, 1 item
    - Muus, Jytte, 1953-1968 May 9; 21 items
      Includes 1968 May 9 Mount Holyoke lecture; recommendations for various grants, Fullbright teaching fellowship and others; curriculum vitae.
    - Mycek, Mary J., 1954-1969; 33 items
      Includes staff appointment; recommendation for;.
      (See also under: American Society of Biological Chemists correspondence. Box no. 3).
    - Myhrman, Rolf, 2 items
  - N-Na (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Nachmansohn, David, 1 item
    - Nagy, Bela F. Grant application review with photocopied grant application, 3 items
    - Najjar, Victor A., 1965-1974; 4 items
    - Nakagawa, Y., 1968-1973; 50 items
      Includes staff appointment; recommendations for; Nakagawa et al reprints.
    - National Academy of Sciences Reviews of tables for Committee on the Handbook of Biological Data: Reviews: Tables on Proteins; Physical Chemical Properties; Plasma Proteins, 8 items
    - National Aeronautics and Space Administration, 2 items
    - National Institutes of Health Correspondent: Julia T. Apter, 3 items
    - Navidi, Marjorie H., 1 item
  - Ne-No (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Neuberger, A., 1960-1973; 11 items
      Includes S.E. Allerton recommendation.
    - Neumann, Hava, 1961-1971; 17 items
      Includes correspondence about pepsin-pepsinogen work.
    - Neurath, Hans Correspondence indicates reviewed mss for Biochemistry; includes correspondence about volume on Proteolytic Enzymes of Methods in Enzymology, 1961-1971; 17 items
    - New York Academy of Sciences, 1 item
    - Nielsen, Sigurd O., 3 items
    - Nissen, Merrill E., 2 items
    - Noda, Lafayette, 1961 May 9-1971; 17 items
      Includes 1961 May 9 Dartmouth Medical School seminar; nomination of Lucile Smith for Garvan award with biographical material on L. Smith.
  - O-On (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Ochert, Dvorah, 3 items
    - Oestreicher, A. Beate, 1961-1971; 65 items
      Includes staff appointment while working toward doctorate; Oestreicher et al reprint.
    - Ohad, I. Job inquiry for Shabtai Bauer, 3 items
    - Oncley, J.L., 1 item
    - Ong, Eng Bee, 1965-1969; 48 items
      Includes staff appointment; recommendation for; Onglet all reprints.
  - Op-Ot (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Oplatka, Avraham, 1965-1973; 21 items
    - Oppenheim, Irwin, 1 item
    - Orekhovich, V.N., 2 items
    - Oren, Mollie, 1 item
    - Orion Research Inc., 1 item
    - Ottesen, Martin and Gerda, 1963-1973; 88 items
      Some correspondence. about memorial honors for K. Linderstrøm-Lang; and Seminars.
      - Carlsberg Laboratory, 1968 September 6
      - Copenhagen, Proteolytic Enzyme Symposium, 1969 circa June 15
      - Carlsberg Laboratory, 1970 August 31
  - P-Pra (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Paecht, Marit, 2 items
    - Palade, George E., 7 items
      Includes Nobel Prize nomination for Palade with biographical material.
    - Paladini, A.C., 1964-1973; 6 items
    - Parker, Sybil, 1 item
    - Parks, W. George, 2 items
    - Patchornik, A., 1961-1973; 7 items
    - Pazur, John H., 3 items
    - Pedersen, Kai O., 1961-1973; 4 items
    - Pedersen, O. Margery, 1 item
    - Perlmann, D., 2 items
    - Perlmann, Peter, 5 items
    - Perutz, Max, 2 items
    - Pharo, Richard L., 2 items
    - Phillips, David C., 14 items
    - Picket, Lucy W. Recommendation for Garvan medal, 2 items
    - Pin, Paul, 2 items
    - Pitt-Rivers, Rosalind, 5 items
    - Pollaczek, Eric H., 2 items
    - Pomerat, Gerald, 2 items
    - Pope, Pauline F., 4 items
    - Porath, J., 2 items
    - Porter, Roger S., 5 items
    - Pratt, Charles, 1 item
  - Pre-Po (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Prescott, J.M. 1969-1974 Some correspondence. about pepsin-pepsinogen work; includes 1973 ca. May 10 Texas A & M seminar, 1969-1973 circa 1974; 57 items (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Press, Elizabeth M., 1959-1973; 41 items (Box 8, Folder 4)
      Includes staff appointment; correspondence. about pepsin-pepsinogen work.
    - Prints, Morton, 16 items (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Pritham, Gordon H., 2 items (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Prywes, M., 2 items (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Putnam, Frank W., 1959 1961 April; 3 items (Box 8, Folder 4)
      About introducing papers for presentation by others at 1959, 1961 April meetings of ASBC in Atlantic City; includes abstracts of each paper.
    - Porter, Rodney R., 1959-1973; 69 items (Box 8, Folder 5)
      Includes nominations for Nobel Prize and Rosenstiel award with Porter biographical material; Porter holograph.
  - R-Ry (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Ramachandran, B.V. Job inquiry; includes reprint, 4 items
    - Ramachandran, G.N., 1 item
    - Ramachandran, N., 2 items
    - Ramakrishnan, C., 1 item
    - Rao, N.V., 5 items
    - Rapin, Annette, 1 item
    - Ratner, Sara, 2 items
    - Reilly, Edith, 1 item
    - Reynolds, Jacqueline, 11 items
    - Reynolds, John H. St. Louis, Mo. Monsanto Laboratories seminar, 1967 December 8; 6 items
    - Ribadeau-Dumas, B., 5 items
    - Richards, Frederic M., 1 item
    - Richter, Dietmar, 2 items
    - Rigbi, Meir, 8 items
    - Rilbe, Harry, 6 items
      Includes attending Stockholm, International Congress Biochem.
    - Rimon, Avraham, 1973 July 1-7; 3 items
    - Rimon, Sara, 1965-1969; 37 items
      Staff appointment; 1966 photograph of Sara Rimon.
    - Robert, Leslie, 5 items
    - Roepke, M.H., 2 items
    - Roseman, Saul, 5 items
    - Rosenblith, Walter, 1 item
    - Rosenheck, Kurt, 2 items
    - Rosenthal, Lois, 2 items
    - Roslansky, John D., 4 items
    - Rovery, Mireille, 3 items
    - Rupley, John A., 1973 January 19; 6 items
      Includes Univ. of Arizona seminar.
    - Russak, B., 2 items
    - Ryle, A.P., 8 items
  - S-Se (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Sachs, Howard. Curriculum vitae, 1 item
    - Saha, Anil, 3 items
    - Saifer, A., 3 items
    - Salzberg, Jane, 1 item
    - Samuel, David, 3 items
    - Sathe, D.V., 3 items
    - Schejter, A. Recommendation for Leon Goldstein, 2 items
    - Schellman, John A., 3 items
    - Scheraga, Harold A., 4 items
    - Schlamowitz, Max, 1960-1972; 25 items
      Includes correspondence. about pepsin-pepsinogen work.
    - Schlesinger, R. Walter. Recommendation for Rosie Wong, 1 item
    - Schmid, Karl, 1963-1971; 17 items
      - Boston University School of Medicine seminars, 1966 May 3 1971 January 28
    - Schmidt, Gerhard (Boston Dispensary), 1953-1960; 3 items
    - Schmidt, Gerhard M.J. (Weizmann Institute), 2 items
    - Schmitt, Francis O., 2 items
    - Schramm, Michael, 1965-1974; 13 items
      Includes promotion recommendation for Y. Lapidot.
    - Schreiber, M., 1 item
    - Schultz, Julius. On becoming member of nominating committee American Chemical Society, Division of Biological Chemistry, 2 items
    - Schwabe, Christian, 2 items
    - Schwartz, James H., 1 item
    - Schwarz, David R., 1 item
    - Schwyzer, R., 2 items
    - Seifter, S., 1 item
    - Sela, Ben Ami. About position for Eziona Sela, 3 items
    - Sela, Eziona, 3 items
    - Sela, Margalit, 1 item
    - Sela, Michael, 1960-1972; 24 items
    - Sen, A., 6 items
    - Sessa, Grazia. Job inquiry, 2 items
    - Severson, Roland G., 2 items
  - Sh-Si (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Shainkin, Ruth, 59 items
      Includes staff appointment; recommendations for; Shainkin et al reprints.
    - Shapiro, B. Promotion recommendation for Yehudith Birk, 3 items
    - Sharon, Nathan, 1968-1974; 29 items
      Includes newspaper article on Stein, Moore, Anfinsen, Nobel Prize winners, in Hebrew; issue of magazine Mada (Hebrew) with article and many photographs of Aharon Katzir-Katchalski.
    - Shaw, Elliott N., 1 item
    - Sheiba, Becky, 5 items
    - Shilo, Mira and Moshe, 3 items
    - Shooter, Eric M., 4 items
    - Shotten, David, 1 item
    - Shull, Kenneth H., 9 items
    - Sigma Xi. Treasurer of Sigma Xi, 1969-1970; 7 items
    - Silberberg, Alex, 1961-1974; 20 items
    - Simonds, Herbert R., 5 items
    - Simpson, Melvin, 3 items
    - Singer, Maxim, 1 item
    - Sinohara, Hyozo, 2 items
  - Sm-Sz (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Small, M.C., 2 items
    - Small, Parker A., 7 items
    - Smillie, Ernest W., 1 item
    - Smillie, L.B., 2 items
    - Smith, Dwight M., 2 items
    - Smith, Emil L., 7 items
      Includes recommendation for Nelly Canaan.
    - Smith, Homer (Woods Hole), 7 items
    - Smith, Lucile, 1961-1973; 4 items
      (See also under: Noda, L. correspondence. Box no. 7).
    - Snyder, Stuart S., 1 item
    - Sober, Herbert A., 1962-1963 October 24, 1971; 18 items
      Includes 1963 Oct. 24 National Cancer Institute seminar; abstract.
    - Socha, Elizabeth, 1 item
    - Sokolovsky, M., 1 item
    - Solomon, A., 5 items
    - Sonenberg, Martin, 2 items
    - Spikes, John D., 2 items
    - Spiro, Robert G., 19 items
      Includes correspondence about phosvitin work.
    - Stahmann, Mark A., 5 items
    - Stecher, E.D., 1 item
    - Steckelman, Ilana, 2 items
    - Steele, Barbara, 2 items
    - Stein, Eric A., 2 items
    - Stein, William H., 4 items
    - Stein, Yeheskiel and Olga, 4 items
    - Steinberg, Izchak Z., 1 item
    - Steiner, Lisa, 2 items
    - Stern, Adolph J., 2 items
    - Stern, Robert, 2 items
    - Stevens, Walter, 2 items
    - Stitzen, Charles W., 1961 April 10-15; 4 items
      About reservations for 1961 Apr. 10-15 Atlantic City, N.J. Federation meeting.
    - Stockmayer, Walter H., 1 item
    - Stollar, James Job inquiry, 2 items
    - Sunderlin, C.E., 1 item
    - Svensson, Harry, 4 items
    - Symposium (Columbia University), 2 items
    - Szuchet, Sara, 12 items